<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Botos Csaba</title>
    <link>https://users.itk.ppke.hu/~botcs/about/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Botos Csaba</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 May 2018 01:01:19 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://users.itk.ppke.hu/~botcs/about/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Local phase encoding (DRAFT)</title>
      <link>https://users.itk.ppke.hu/~botcs/about/project/2d-fft/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2018 01:01:19 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://users.itk.ppke.hu/~botcs/about/project/2d-fft/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Atrial fibrillation detection</title>
      <link>https://users.itk.ppke.hu/~botcs/about/project/physionet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2018 00:51:25 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://users.itk.ppke.hu/~botcs/about/project/physionet/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PPCU Sam</title>
      <link>https://users.itk.ppke.hu/~botcs/about/project/sam/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2018 00:04:36 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://users.itk.ppke.hu/~botcs/about/project/sam/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dense 3D reconstruction with autonomous agents (DRAFT)</title>
      <link>https://users.itk.ppke.hu/~botcs/about/project/coop-drl-3d/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2018 00:00:50 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://users.itk.ppke.hu/~botcs/about/project/coop-drl-3d/</guid>
      <description>Combine Intel&amp;rsquo;s navigation with OpenAI cooperative agents on Collaborative Dense recognition task</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Manifold reconstruction (DRAFT)</title>
      <link>https://users.itk.ppke.hu/~botcs/about/project/coop-drl/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2018 00:00:50 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://users.itk.ppke.hu/~botcs/about/project/coop-drl/</guid>
      <description> DeepMind parallel agent optim. where originally with Wasserstein GAN we would like to reduce the earth mover&amp;rsquo;s distance in order to approximate such function we have to enforce Lipschitz property to do so we can use weight clipping -&amp;gt; Bad &amp;hellip; or gradient penalty -&amp;gt; globally wrong, locally ok Why not use TVG collaborative reconstruction on the latent space  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improve 3D scene reconstruction by semantic mesh generation or factorization (DRAFT)</title>
      <link>https://users.itk.ppke.hu/~botcs/about/project/meshrec/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 23:41:17 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://users.itk.ppke.hu/~botcs/about/project/meshrec/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Palace of Wonders</title>
      <link>https://users.itk.ppke.hu/~botcs/about/project/csopa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 20:04:21 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://users.itk.ppke.hu/~botcs/about/project/csopa/</guid>
      <description>Five AI workshop sessions throughout the 2017-2018 academic year on recent advances in Deep Learning and its applications.
Motivation The goal of these workshops is to dismiss fear and ignorance in people who are concerned about AI by showing true potential and downsides, possibilities and requirements of current state of the art algorithms. I wanted demistify the black magic done by tech giants by showing interactive demos of actual AI tools (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Next please</title>
      <link>https://users.itk.ppke.hu/~botcs/about/project/nextplease/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2018 19:43:21 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://users.itk.ppke.hu/~botcs/about/project/nextplease/</guid>
      <description>If I think about how the number of neural connections (the synapse density) changes w.r.t the age in general I would naively say that the older we get, the more knowledge we have and even if the number of neurons decreases that knowledge is expressed in connections between nerve cells, therefore the total number of connections had to increase, or at least stagnate. However ontogenesis studies tells us a different story&amp;hellip; The main thing that I recognise is -mathematically speaking- the decreasing complexity of the connectivity graph of the nervous tissue after the first year of birth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Temporal Attention mechanism</title>
      <link>https://users.itk.ppke.hu/~botcs/about/project/attention/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2018 19:43:21 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://users.itk.ppke.hu/~botcs/about/project/attention/</guid>
      <description>The general idea of thalamo-cortico-thalamo circuitry in vertebrae was against the traditional description of the thalamus being a simple relay of visual information between the eyes and the visual cortex. In an experiment it was shown, that if the connections were inhibited between other cortices aside from the visual resulted in losing of sight - which implied in the first case the revision of the original hypothesis. To sum up what we know so far, it is believed additional connections to other parts add both low level contextual information, such as proprioception and high level information like enhancing semantic edges of objects, correction based on temporal continuity, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>